<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Transplant on Mike needs a kidney</title>
    <link>http://mikeneedsakidney.ca/tags/transplant/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Transplant on Mike needs a kidney</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-ca</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 15:02:46 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://mikeneedsakidney.ca/tags/transplant/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cycler at home</title>
      <link>http://mikeneedsakidney.ca/posts/cycler_at_home/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 15:02:46 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://mikeneedsakidney.ca/posts/cycler_at_home/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, last week I was on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mikeneedsakidney.ca/posts/dialysis_training/&#34;&gt;dialysis training&lt;/a&gt;,&#xA;and now it&amp;rsquo;s the weekend. On friday, my dialysis supplies were delivered and my&#xA;cycler machine was set up in my bedroom.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The nice guys who delivered my supplies carried them into my office for me, as&#xA;I specified. And damn, did they deliver a lot of stuff.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/baxter_boxes.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Boxes in my office&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The initial order was put in by the nurses, and they are teaching me how to&#xA;submit follow-up orders myself. I&amp;rsquo;m using a lot of google calendar. And there is&#xA;so much stuff that it&amp;rsquo;s overwhelming, but luckily my wife is good at organizing&#xA;stuff. While we were in the hospital being taught, she was making lists and&#xA;ordering shit on Amazon. We stopped by a dollar store for some organizational&#xA;compartments for drawers, and now my bed&amp;rsquo;s end-table is very well organized.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dialysis training</title>
      <link>http://mikeneedsakidney.ca/posts/dialysis_training/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 12:16:19 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://mikeneedsakidney.ca/posts/dialysis_training/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So last week, I spent four days of the work week at the hospital taking a course&#xA;on Peritoneal Dialysis. Yeah, fun. Want to spend days in a hospital that is a&#xA;major pain to reach due to horrible traffic and lack of urban planning, where&#xA;they surgically modify your body and then teach you how to live with those&#xA;modifications. Sound fun?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The people were&amp;hellip;awesome. The nurses, orderlies, and the doctors could not have&#xA;been better in how I was treated. How &lt;em&gt;we&lt;/em&gt; were treated, actually, since my&#xA;amazing wife came with me. I mean, day one is scary enough, since they are&#xA;planning to cut you open and pull out the PD catheter so you can use it. They&amp;rsquo;re&#xA;going to use local anesthesia, but I&amp;rsquo;m always worried that it&amp;rsquo;s going to hurt&#xA;anyway.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parasites</title>
      <link>http://mikeneedsakidney.ca/posts/parasites/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 18:24:37 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://mikeneedsakidney.ca/posts/parasites/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m surprised that it took this long. I&amp;rsquo;ve had the website up for a while now,&#xA;and I just appeared in Glen Gower&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.glengower.ca/&#34;&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt;.&#xA;He&amp;rsquo;s our local city councillor, and was kind enough to give me a few minutes of&#xA;his time recently.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But not everyone is quite so altruistic. I just received an email from a &amp;ldquo;woman&amp;rdquo;&#xA;(who knows?) asking if I am looking for a kidney, when obviously I am. I pointed&#xA;her at the Ottawa Hospital &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ottawahospital.on.ca/en/clinical-services/deptpgrmcs/programs/kidney-donation/living-donation/&#34;&gt;living donor&#xA;program&lt;/a&gt;,&#xA;and then did a quick search on her email address out of curiosity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Well, it&#39;s official</title>
      <link>http://mikeneedsakidney.ca/posts/well_its_official/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 19:19:56 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://mikeneedsakidney.ca/posts/well_its_official/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, I just had a regular check-up with the CKD clinic. Sadly my kidney function&#xA;is now 9%. Yes, single digits.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The nephrologist said that it&amp;rsquo;s important to find the &amp;ldquo;sweet spot&amp;rdquo; to start&#xA;dialysis, between being strong enough to learn how, but close enough to really&#xA;need it. And she felt that this is that time, so I am now signed up for a 4-day&#xA;peritoneal dialysis course in about 2 weeks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coming soon</title>
      <link>http://mikeneedsakidney.ca/posts/coming_soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://mikeneedsakidney.ca/posts/coming_soon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, it would seem that my hoping, and occasional praying, for my condition to&#xA;turn around was, admittedly, a waste of time. Not really a surprise.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was supposed to go to the course on Peritoneal Dialysis this month, but given&#xA;that my symptoms are not quite where the CKD clinic expects them to be, they&#xA;suggested that we wait until my assessment early next month to make a decision.&#xA;There is a very good chance that at the end of that I&amp;rsquo;ll be signed up for the&#xA;course immediately.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sumi&#39;s story</title>
      <link>http://mikeneedsakidney.ca/posts/sumis_story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 14:10:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://mikeneedsakidney.ca/posts/sumis_story/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, I asked an old curling buddy (yes, those exist) about his experiences with&#xA;kidney disease. He&amp;rsquo;s farther along than I am, having just had a transplant&#xA;(yay!), so clearly I can learn from his experience.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He has gratiously permitted me to post this. I quote:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hi Mike and Maria,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Feel free to use anything I&amp;rsquo;ve written in your blog posts or on Facebook. All&#xA;dates are rough, I am using My chart, but some of the data is really buried&#xA;and there isn&amp;rsquo;t a really good search engine on Mychart.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
